# **ABHINNA AKASH**

Senior Software Engineer

+91 6200831675



abhinn.aakash@gmail.com



Chandigarh



# **SUMMARY**

I am a highly skilled and experienced software engineer based in Chandigarh. With 5 years of experience under my belt, I have honed my skills in ReactJS, MERN stack, Node, ExpressJs, and React Native. My passion for coding and problem-solving has driven me to constantly learn and stay updated with the latest technologies in the ever-evolving field of software development.

## SKILLS

- Hands on experience on React JS, TypeScriot, JavaScript, React Native, Redux, Contex tAPI etc
- Strong organizational and timemanagement skills
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team

## **TECHNOLOGY**

- React JS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node JS
- Git
- CSS
- HTML5
- AWS
- Firebase
- Agile
- GIT
- Express JS

# **EDUCATION**

## Emax Institute of Engg & Tech.

Bachelor's of Technology in Computer Science From KUK 2014 – 2018

#### J D Public School

12th from CBSE 2012 - 2014

#### Saraswati Vidya Mandir

10th from CBSE 2012

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Trantor Software Pvt. Ltd. | Dec 2022 - Present

- VMWare Config Engine: This Application is useful in configuring cloud products in process of CPQ system.
- VMWare Estimator: The Estimator Application is Responsible for estimating price while adding products of custom configuration in our cart.
- VMWare Configurator: This Application is shared package custom designed for Estimator & CE team to be used for managing product data based on Quoting validation rules.

## Senior Software Developer

E-nest Technology | Jan 2019 - Dec 2022

- Universal Weather & Aviation Wings: Development of Wings application with different modules bonded together with module federation Micro-Frontend. The application is built with ReactJS, AGGrid and Material UI.
- LUCY Bank App: Decorated with custom animations in React native, the application is architected in a way to be used as pocket management and banking application. Especially developed for targeting Singapore Female entrepreneurs.
- **SBChat App:** Based on React Native, SBChat is a hybrid mobile application able to establish communication between 2 people and a group. It is powered by Firebase FCM for seamless communication.
- Lotto Social: Using this Application, users can have access to exclusive offers and lotteries and get points. The Application is built using React, Firebase and Branch IO.